Fri, 22 May 2020 09:11:17 -0500, Memorial Day Weekend Update from the Library of Congress, 42788665, https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn , Friends,, I hope that you and your families remain well this month. On Monday, we will observe Memorial Day, honoring the service and sacrifices of members of our armed forces. Our nation is strong and it endures because of the men and women who give it their all in protecting and preserving our democracy., , . In the meantime, we invite you to continue to explore our content digitally through the resources listed below, and to connect with us on our social media channels., Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress On Friday, May 8, the Veterans History Project (VHP) commemorated the end of World War II in Europe, also known as V-E Day, by releasing a new installment of the VHP online exhibit, Experiencing War. In this new online feature, you can explore the personal stories of 15 World War II veterans and what the end of the war meant for them.&nbsp; Although some cities and states are starting to open up a little, we have a feeling it will be a while before we&rsquo;re going out to concerts, theaters, jams, or open mics to perform or enjoy live music and performing arts. At the Library of Congress, we have an amazing online archive of folk music and folklife which you can explore right from home, and we&rsquo;d like to offer a suggestion: why not learn a song, tune, poem, or story from the archive, make a recording or video of yourself performing it, and post it online? Or make a work of art based on one of our photos, or write a story or poem based on our materials. We&rsquo;d love to see what you come up with! Folks from all genres and creators of all art forms are invited to interpret a field recording, video, photo, or manuscript from the AFC Archive. You don&rsquo;t need to be a professional in order to participate!  The Library of Congress and Portland Ovations will present the International Contemporary Ensemble in the Library&rsquo;s first interactive digital concert &ndash; &ldquo;Aural Explorations: Farrin, Fure and Messiaen&rdquo; &ndash; on Thursday, May 28, at 7 p.m. Eastern time., The concert will feature the world premiere of the Library co-commissioned composition by Suzanne Farrin titled &ldquo;Nacht,&rdquo; capping a season-long celebration of women composers and performers honoring the centennial of women&rsquo;s suffrage. The concert will also feature a world premiere of Ashley Fure&rsquo;s &ldquo;Interior Listening Protocol 1&rdquo; paired with Olivier Messiaen&rsquo;s &ldquo;Louange &agrave; l'&Eacute;ternit&eacute; de J&eacute;sus&rdquo; for ondes Martenot and Suzanne Farrin&rsquo;s &ldquo;Polvere et Ombra.&rdquo; May is Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month. The Library of Congress, National Archives and Records Administration, National Endowment for the Humanities, National Gallery of Art, National Park Service, Smithsonian Institution and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum join in paying tribute to the generations of Asian and Pacific Islanders who have enriched America's history and are instrumental in its future success. Visit this multi-institution web portal hosted by the Library of Congress for featured content and resources May is Jewish American Heritage Month. The Library of Congress, National Archives and Records Administration, National Endowment for the Humanities, National Gallery of Art, National Park Service and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum join in paying tribute to the generations of Jewish Americans who have helped form the fabric of American history, culture and society. Visit this multi-institution web portal hosted by the Library of Congress for featured content and resources We are more grateful than ever for all that you do to keep us strong. Whether you support the Library with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of our collective past, present, and future., ., &nbsp;, 

Thu, 14 May 2020 16:05:42 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: Newspaper Navigator Announced: Extracting Photos, Maps, and Comics from over 16 Million Newspaper Pages!, 42708071, https://labs.loc.gov/work/experiments/newspaper-navigator/?loclr=eacam , Newspaper Navigator Announced: Extracting Photos, Maps, and Comics from over 16 Million Newspaper Pages!, May 14, 2020, ., .

Fri, 24 Apr 2020 07:00:18 -0500, The Library of Congress Turns 220, 42469053, https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn , , Since that beginning 220 years ago, the Library has grown to become the largest library in the world with a collection of more than 170 million items that document human creativity and achievement across the centuries and around the globe.,  to explore the Library&rsquo;s digital collections from home.,  and to continue to engage with us through some of the resources listed below. We look forward to continuing to serve you during this season and beyond., Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress Preview the new Citizen DJ app from Innovator-in-Residence Brian Foo, and discover how to make Hip Hop using the Library&rsquo;s music collection. Presented by LC Labs., , , ,  lecture that will explore how creators&mdash;who through the copyright system can earn a living from their work&mdash;can play a key role in creating a vision of a green future and its untold benefits. Registration required., , A Law Day 2020 event presented by the Law Library of Congress and the American Bar Association. Registration required, space is limited., , Prize-winning science writer David Quammen discusses his book "Spillover," in which he tracks the animal origins of human diseases through the centuries, with National Book Festival Co-Chairman David Rubenstein The Archive of Recorded Poetry and Literature at the Library of Congress dates back to 1943 and contains nearly two thousand recordings of poets and prose writers participating in literary events at the Library&rsquo;s Capitol Hill campus as well as sessions at the Library&rsquo;s Recording Laboratory. New recordings added for 2020 include a 1978 reunion reading featuring 13 of our Consultants in Poetry, and Gwendolyn Brooks reading poems (including the iconic &ldquo;We Real Cool&rdquo;) in the Jefferson Recording Laboratory in 1961 Encourage kids of all ages to use their creativity to complete activities inspired by the Library&rsquo;s collections. With simple items found around the house and items from our website, kids can Cook Up History, Make a Mini-Book, Color Our Collections, and so much more. Visit the Resources for Family Engagement page to download activity kits and get started today We are grateful to all those who transcribe and review pages on the Library's virtual volunteering project By the People launched in 2018. As of the Library&rsquo;s 220th birthday today, volunteers have transcribed over 125,000 pages from the papers of suffragists including Mary Church Terrell, Lucy Stone, and Susan B Anthony, civil rights activist Rosa Parks, poet Walt Whitman, President Abraham Lincoln, and many others. Once a whole item such as a journal or letter is complete, it is brought back to loc.gov where it radically improves search and discovery for patrons, and accessibility those who use screen readers National Preservation Week is April 26 &ndash; May 2. Preservation of the world's largest collection is accomplished through a broad range of activities distributed across the Library. Learn more about these preservation activities and the work to keep the collections available for the next 220 years and beyond The Copyright Office has announced updated flexibility surrounding registration deposits and timing provisions for those affected by COVID-19 as outlined in the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security (CARES) Act. Visit the Copyright Office COVID-19 page for more info We are more grateful than ever for all that you do to keep us strong. Whether you support the Library with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of our collective past, present, and future., ., &nbsp;, 

Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:43:14 -0500, A Message from the Librarian of Congress, 42326672, https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn , Friends,, I hope that you are taking care or yourselves and your families as we settle into a new normal amid the COVID-19 pandemic. During these challenging times, the Library of Congress buildings remain closed to the public with all public events currently canceled through May 11. However, while our physical doors may be closed, we are still here for you., The Library&rsquo;s vast online resources offer unlimited opportunities to discover something new for families, educators, researchers and anyone curious enough to join us., . Below you will find just a few ways that you can continue to find excellent programs and content from the Library., ., Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress  Visit fascinating exhibitions online including our current exhibition on Rosa Parks which showcases rarely seen materials that offer an intimate view of Rosa Parks and documents her life and activism&mdash;creating a rich opportunity for viewers to discover new dimensions to their understanding of this seminal figure  Dive into the Library&rsquo;s digital collections to explore just about any topic imaginable. Click through historical portraits and cityscape photographs, listen to sound recordings and oral histories, study American history and world cultures, discover local history and folklife traditions, explore maps, music, manuscripts and so much more. With digitized collections of more than 2.4 million items, it&rsquo;s all at your fingertips  remains open! Submit questions to receive research or reference help., &shy; and consider making a gift to ensure the Library&rsquo;s resources help everyone who needs them., &nbsp;, 

Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:00:16 -0600, Thanks for Your Support!, 41049881, https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev , Thank you for all you do to support the nation&rsquo;s Library. With new books, films, and music arriving every day, the Library of Congress is your place to discover new ideas. Whether you support us with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of the world&rsquo;s past, present, and future.

Fri, 20 Dec 2019 09:15:14 -0600, Make Your Gift Before We Close the Books on 2019!, 41049710, https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev , The Library of Congress is your place to discover new ideas. Visit our new exhibitions, join us for our events and educational programs and participate in our activities that connect you with millions of people around the world.

Tue, 03 Dec 2019 09:00:42 -0600, TODAY: Ignite the Power of Ideas, 40789914, https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev , &mdash;a day when your gift makes a difference and a statement., The Library of Congress depends on the support of people like you for its exhibitions, programs, events and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with its unique collections, experts and services., , to make a gift to the nation&rsquo;s library, your gateway to understanding the world.

Wed, 27 Nov 2019 09:42:27 -0600, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  119 YEARS AGO: "The Gobble," San Francisco Call," Nov. 24, 1901, 40792597, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-11-24/ed-1/seq-8/?loclr=eacam , Not enjoying the Thanksgiving spirit? Here's an unusual poem by Clarence V. Odell describing the turkey-eat-turkey dynamic of a 'gobble,' another name for a flock of the big birds (also known as a 'rafter')., One ate his head off, then there were eight....", Pity the turkeys... it rarely ends well for them!,  and follow us all the time on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!

Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:29:02 -0600, Ignite the Power of Ideas, 40752625, https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev , we ask you to make a gift to the Library of Congress in celebration of #GivingTuesday&mdash;a global giving movement., Your gift supports exhibitions, events, programs and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with the unique collections, experts and services here at the nation&rsquo;s library., ,  to see what&rsquo;s new!

Fri, 25 Oct 2019 15:21:53 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Checking Out Baseball’s World Series in Washington 1924, 1925 and 1933, 40389924, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F1%2F1924&amp;date2=10%2F10%2F1933&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=&amp;proxtext=washington+world+series&amp;proxdistance=10&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam , 

Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:46:48 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: "FIRE! Destruction of Chicago!" Chicago Tribune, Oct. 11, 1871, 40166993, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014064/1871-10-11/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam , !

Fri, 16 Aug 2019 11:53:46 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: CORRECTION - NEH Announces 2019 Awards for the National Digital Newspaper Program, Adding Partners in Rhode Island, Virgin Islands and Wyoming!, 39388374, https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide , An error was made in a previous message regarding the number of partners to date in the National Digital Newspaper Program. Corrected message below:,  for details. Since 2005, cultural institutions in 50 states and territories have joined the program, jointly sponsored by the NEH and LOC, and contributed more than 15 million digitized historical American newspaper pages, published between 1789 and 1963 in 19 different languages, to the collection.,  and read more about it! Follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!!

Fri, 16 Aug 2019 10:00:01 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  NEH Announces 2019 Awards for the National Digital Newspaper Program, adding partners in Rhode Island, Virgin Islands and Wyoming!, 39387099, https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide ,  for details. Since 2005, cultural institutions in 49 states and territories have joined the program, jointly sponsored by the NEH and LC, and contributed more than 15 million digitized historical American newspaper pages, published between 1789 and 1963 in 19 different languages, to the collection.,  and read more about it! Follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!!

Fri, 12 Jul 2019 16:25:56 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  100 YEARS AGO: "Wilson Blocks Daylight Saving Appeal," The Evening World, July 12, 1919, 38871710, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1919-07-12/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam ,  and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!, &nbsp;

Thu, 06 Jun 2019 15:04:04 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  75 Years Ago: “ALLIES SMASHING INLAND,” The Wilmington Morning Star, June 07, 1944, 38383009, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78002169/1944-06-07/ed-1/seq-1/?eacam , ! (And then follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!)

Tue, 21 May 2019 10:57:51 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Celebrate 15 Million Pages with Us! Find Out More and Join our Twitter #ChronAmParty Today (May 21)!, 38155249, http://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/05/chronicling-america-15-million-and-counting/?loclr=eacam ,  all day Tuesday, May 21 (today!). Follow the threads and find out about all the fun kinds of &ldquo;15 Million&rdquo; things we&rsquo;ve discovered in Chronicling America &ndash; feel free to celebrate with us and tweet your own discoveries! Just add #ChronAmParty and #15MillionPages to your tweet to join the party!,  digital libraries blog. Understand and interact with our newspapers in a different way using maps, time-based views, charts of language and ethnic press in American newspapers and more!,  and follow us all the time on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!

Wed, 15 May 2019 14:57:13 -0500, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Happy National Chocolate Chip Cookie Day! (May 15), 38085692, https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2017236974/1940-10-10/ed-1/seq-19/#date1=1789&amp;index=19&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced&amp;language=&amp;sequence=0&amp;words=Chip+Chocolate+Cookies&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;date2=1963&amp;ortext=&amp;proxtext=chocolate+chip+cookie&amp;phrasetext=&amp;andtext=&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1?loclr=eacam , 

Fri, 08 Mar 2019 15:50:12 -0600, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Celebrate International Women's Day With Us!, 37043146, https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/03/international-womens-day/?loclr=eacam ,  and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!

Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:37:09 -0600, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  86 YEARS AGO: “Popular Popcorn,” The Midland Journal, February 17, 1933, 36256316, http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060136/1933-02-17/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1789&amp;index=16&amp;rows=20&amp;words=POPCORN+popcorn+Popcorn&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=popcorn&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1 , 

Mon, 31 Dec 2018 07:15:13 -0600, Still Time for Last-Minute Giving, 35915321, https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev , 

Wed, 26 Dec 2018 08:00:19 -0600, Make a Year-End Gift to the Nation's Library, 35915275, https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev, 
, , Your gift can:, <ul style="text-align: start;">
Inspire curiosity in children to read more books and reflect on the&nbsp;power of books to change their lives, Ignite thoughtful conversation among current and future generations of students and scholars, Illuminate the minds of people like you who use the resources of the nation's Library here in Washington or via the Internet in their own homes and communities, </ul>
With the help of supporters like you, we can spark the imagination of people of all ages with programs that open the Library&rsquo;s doors wide to all., , &nbsp;, , 

Wed, 12 Dec 2018 09:16:26 -0600, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Join the National Digital Newspaper Program in 2019! Applications due Jan. 15, 2019, 35782124, http://1.usa.gov/1ye8EKz , 

Tue, 27 Nov 2018 07:00:15 -0600, Make Your Gift to the Nation's Library, 35429411, https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev , &nbsp;

Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:37:06 -0600, Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  100 YEARS AGO: "Menu and Recipes for Your 'Victory' Thanksgiving Dinner," The Evening World, Nov. 26, 1918, 35463812, http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-11-26/ed-1/seq-14/#date1=1918&amp;index=1&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Recipes+Thanksgiving&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1918&amp;proxtext=thanksgiving+recipe&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1 , &nbsp;

Tue, 20 Nov 2018 12:52:36 -0600, Spark a Lifelong Adventure of Learning, 35429359, https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev , 