<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers</title>
    <link>http://www.loc.gov/index.html</link>
    <description>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers</description>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 22 May 2020 09:11:17 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Memorial Day Weekend Update from the Library of Congress</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">42788665</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285149/cdh2_original.jpg" alt="Carla D. Hayden, Librarian of Congress" title="" width="210" height="210" style="float: left;" />Friends,</p>
<p>I hope that you and your families remain well this month. On Monday, we will observe Memorial Day, honoring the service and sacrifices of members of our armed forces. Our nation is strong and it endures because of the men and women who give it their all in protecting and preserving our democracy.</p>
<p>Since 2000, the Veterans History Project (VHP) at the Library has been committed to collecting, preserving and making accessible the personal accounts of American war veterans. And while many of the stories collected are from living veterans, there are thousands that were donated posthumously by family members looking to preserve the legacies of their loved ones. &ldquo;Say Their Name. Learn Their Story&rdquo; is a wonderful blog post highlighting the stories of individuals who have given their lives in service of our country, and who are memorialized in the VHP collections. Read more here: <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/folklife/2019/05/say-their-name-learn-their-story/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://blogs.loc.gov/folklife/2019/05/say-their-name-learn-their-story/</a></p>
<p>The Library of Congress buildings remain closed to the public, with all public events currently canceled until further notice. Visit our web site for full, <a href="https://www.loc.gov/about/pandemic-information/for-public/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">up-to-date information about our response to COVID-19</a>. In the meantime, we invite you to continue to explore our content digitally through the resources listed below, and to connect with us on our social media channels.</p>
<p>Sincerely,<br />Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/05/3396389/war_original.png" alt="VHP Experiencing War banners" title="" width="806" height="115" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Veterans History Project</strong></p>
<p>Personal narratives, correspondence, and visual materials are collected and made available so that future generations may hear directly from veterans and better understand the realities of war. Learn more about this important project as well how to collect and submit veterans&rsquo; stories by visiting <a href="https://www.loc.gov/vets/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/vets/</a>.</p>
<p><strong>Experiencing War: Stories from the Veterans History Project</strong></p>
<p>On Friday, May 8, the Veterans History Project (VHP) commemorated the end of World War II in Europe, also known as V-E Day, by releasing a new installment of the VHP online exhibit, Experiencing War. In this new online feature, you can explore the personal stories of 15 World War II veterans and what the end of the war meant for them.&nbsp;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-035/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/item/prn-20-035/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/05/3396511/folklife-image_original.jpg" alt="Musician image" title="" width="570" height="321" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>#</strong><strong>FolklifeArchiveChallenge<br /></strong></p>
<p>Although some cities and states are starting to open up a little, we have a feeling it will be a while before we&rsquo;re going out to concerts, theaters, jams, or open mics to perform or enjoy live music and performing arts. At the Library of Congress, we have an amazing online archive of folk music and folklife which you can explore right from home, and we&rsquo;d like to offer a suggestion: why not learn a song, tune, poem, or story from the archive, make a recording or video of yourself performing it, and post it online? Or make a work of art based on one of our photos, or write a story or poem based on our materials. We&rsquo;d love to see what you come up with! Folks from all genres and creators of all art forms are invited to interpret a field recording, video, photo, or manuscript from the AFC Archive. You don&rsquo;t need to be a professional in order to participate!</p>
<p>Learn more about the challenge and how to participate:<br /><a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/folklife/2020/05/spending-a-lot-of-time-at-home-take-the-archive-challenge/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blogs.loc.gov/folklife/2020/05/spending-a-lot-of-time-at-home-take-the-archive-challenge/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Suffrage History Webinar May 27<br /></strong></p>
<p><span style="color: black;">The Library&rsquo;s Janice Ruth, curator of our Shall Not Be Denied: Women Fight for the Vote exhibition, will join curators from the National Archives and Records Administration and the Smithsonian&rsquo;s National Portait Gallery for &ldquo;Curator&rsquo;s Cut: An Inside Look at DC&rsquo;s Suffrage Exhibits.&rdquo; This free webinar is being hosted by the </span><span style="color: #1f497d;">Women&rsquo;s Suffrage Centennial Commission</span><span style="color: black;">. </span></p>
<p><span style="color: black;">Register here:&nbsp;<a href="https://bit.ly/2TjoWow" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><span style="padding: 0in;">https://bit.ly/2TjoWow</span></a> <br /></span></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/05/3396505/aural-explorations-concert_original.jpg" alt="Concert imageg" title="" width="508" height="279" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Virtual Concert May 28<br /></strong></p>
<p>The Library of Congress and Portland Ovations will present the International Contemporary Ensemble in the Library&rsquo;s first interactive digital concert &ndash; &ldquo;Aural Explorations: Farrin, Fure and Messiaen&rdquo; &ndash; on Thursday, May 28, at 7 p.m. Eastern time.</p>
<p>The concert will feature the world premiere of the Library co-commissioned composition by Suzanne Farrin titled &ldquo;Nacht,&rdquo; capping a season-long celebration of women composers and performers honoring the centennial of women&rsquo;s suffrage. The concert will also feature a world premiere of Ashley Fure&rsquo;s &ldquo;Interior Listening Protocol 1&rdquo; paired with Olivier Messiaen&rsquo;s &ldquo;Louange &agrave; l'&Eacute;ternit&eacute; de J&eacute;sus&rdquo; for ondes Martenot and Suzanne Farrin&rsquo;s &ldquo;Polvere et Ombra.&rdquo;</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-037/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/item/prn-20-037/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/05/3396488/asian_original.png" alt="Asian Pacific American Heritage Month" title="" width="822" height="189" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Asian Pacific American Heritage Month<br /></strong></p>
<p>May is Asian/Pacific American Heritage Month. The Library of Congress, National Archives and Records Administration, National Endowment for the Humanities, National Gallery of Art, National Park Service, Smithsonian Institution and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum join in paying tribute to the generations of Asian and Pacific Islanders who have enriched America's history and are instrumental in its future success. Visit this multi-institution web portal hosted by the Library of Congress for featured content and resources.</p>
<p><a href="https://asianpacificheritage.gov/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">asianpacificheritage.gov/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/05/3396500/jewish_original.png" alt="Jewish American Heritage Month" title="" width="826" height="157" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Jewish American Heritage Month</strong></p>
<p>May is Jewish American Heritage Month. The Library of Congress, National Archives and Records Administration, National Endowment for the Humanities, National Gallery of Art, National Park Service and United States Holocaust Memorial Museum join in paying tribute to the generations of Jewish Americans who have helped form the fabric of American history, culture and society. Visit this multi-institution web portal hosted by the Library of Congress for featured content and resources.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.jewishheritagemonth.gov/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">jewishheritagemonth.gov/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285068/gov-header_original.jpg" alt="Library of Congress" title="" width="600" height="190" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Support the Library</strong></p>
<p>We are more grateful than ever for all that you do to keep us strong. Whether you support the Library with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of our collective past, present, and future.</p>
<p>If you haven't yet had a chance to give and you're in a position to donate, please consider making a gift at<span style="color: #1f497d;"> </span><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/donate</a>/<span style="color: #1f497d;"></span>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 16:05:42 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: Newspaper Navigator Announced: Extracting Photos, Maps, and Comics from over 16 Million Newspaper Pages!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">42708071</guid>
      <link>https://labs.loc.gov/work/experiments/newspaper-navigator/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<h2>Newspaper Navigator Announced: Extracting Photos, Maps, and Comics from over 16 Million Newspaper Pages!</h2>
<p>May 14, 2020</p>
<p>Last week the Library of Congress Labs team <a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2020/04/newspaper-navigator-surfaces-treasure-trove-of-historic-images-get-a-sneak-peek-at-upcoming-data-jam/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">shared some exciting news</a> about the first phase of the <em>Newspaper Navigator</em> project. Led by Ben Lee, Innovator-in-Residence at the Library of Congress, <em>Newspaper Navigator</em> uses machine learning techniques to extract visual content such as photographs, illustrations, maps, and cartoons from the 16+ million pages in <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chronicling America</a>.</p>
<p>Read more about the project on the <a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2020/04/newspaper-navigator-surfaces-treasure-trove-of-historic-images-get-a-sneak-peek-at-upcoming-data-jam/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Signal Blog</a> and consult <a href="https://github.com/LibraryOfCongress/newspaper-navigator?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" class="external" rel="noopener">Ben's repo</a>, which includes code, a whitepaper, and demos, all available without restriction. Stay up to date on the project by visiting the <a href="https://labs.loc.gov/work/experiments/newspaper-navigator/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Newspaper Navigator project page</a>.</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 07:00:18 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>The Library of Congress Turns 220</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">42469053</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285149/cdh2_original.jpg" alt="Carla D. Hayden, Librarian of Congress" title="" width="210" height="210" style="float: left;" /><em>In 1800, as part of an act of Congress providing for the removal of the new national government from Philadelphia to Washington, President John Adams approved an act of Congress providing $5,000 for books for the use of Congress&mdash;the beginning of the Library of Congress.</em></p>
<p>Since that beginning 220 years ago, the Library has grown to become the largest library in the world with a collection of more than 170 million items that document human creativity and achievement across the centuries and around the globe.</p>
<p>Collecting and providing access to these collections takes on a new meaning and significance in our current world. With social distancing as the norm, and more time spent at home, we want to continue to highlight ways to connect with our content, our knowledgeable staff, and each other during these times. From April 24 to 30, you can celebrate the Library&rsquo;s 220th birthday by participating in online programs from across the Library, reading themed posts on our blogs and social media channels, and <a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-032/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">downloading our brand new app</a> to explore the Library&rsquo;s digital collections from home.</p>
<p>The Library of Congress buildings remain closed to the public, with all public events currently canceled through July 1. Visit our web site for <a href="https://www.loc.gov/about/pandemic-information/for-public/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full, up-to-date information about our response to COVID-19</a>. In the meantime, we invite you to <a href="https://www.loc.gov/engage/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">our virtual birthday celebration</a> and to continue to engage with us through some of the resources listed below. We look forward to continuing to serve you during this season and beyond.</p>
<p>Sincerely,<br />Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>SPECIAL 220th BIRTHDAY VIDEO EVENTS<br /></strong></p>
<p><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3317774/citdj_original.jpg" alt="Citizen DJ" title="" width="210" height="185" style="float: right;" /><a href="https://www.facebook.com/libraryofcongress/videos/2921402977940233/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Citizen DJ Premiere &amp; Virtual Masterclass</a><strong><br /></strong><em>Friday, April 24, 3 p.m. ET</em><strong><br /></strong></p>
<p>Preview the new Citizen DJ app from Innovator-in-Residence Brian Foo, and discover how to make Hip Hop using the Library&rsquo;s music collection. Presented by LC Labs.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.facebook.com/pg/libraryofcongress/videos/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">America's Greatest Library: History of the Library of Congress</a><strong><br /></strong><em>Saturday, April 25, 1 p.m. ET</em></p>
<p><a href="https://guides.loc.gov/jason-reynolds/grab-the-mic/wrr" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Write. Right. Rite</a>. A "Grab the Mic: Tell Your Story" video series with Jason Reynolds, National Ambassador for Young People's Literature.<strong><br /></strong><em>Tuesday, April 28, 10:30 a.m. ET</em></p>
<p><a href="https://www.copyright.gov/copyrightmatters/green-future2020/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Awareness to Action: Innovate for a Green Future</a><strong><br /></strong><em>Wednesday, April 29, 11 a.m. ET</em></p>
<p>Join the U.S. Copyright Office for their next <a href="https://www.copyright.gov/copyrightmatters/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Copyright Matters</a> lecture that will explore how creators&mdash;who through the copyright system can earn a living from their work&mdash;can play a key role in creating a vision of a green future and its untold benefits. Registration required.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.eventbrite.com/e/law-day-2020-online-event-tickets-101727070406" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Social Movement Changing America: The Legacies of the 19th Amendment</a><strong><br /></strong><em>Thursday, April 30, 3:30 p.m. ET</em></p>
<p>A Law Day 2020 event presented by the Law Library of Congress and the American Bar Association. Registration required, space is limited.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/programs/national-book-festival/national-book-festival-presents/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Spillover: Animal Infections and the Next Human Pandemic</a><strong><br /></strong><em>Thursday, April 30, 7 p.m. ET</em></p>
<p>Prize-winning science writer David Quammen discusses his book "Spillover," in which he tracks the animal origins of human diseases through the centuries, with National Book Festival Co-Chairman David Rubenstein.</p>
<p><em>Discover more ways to engage with the Library during our birthday week and beyond:</em> <br /><a href="https://www.loc.gov/engage/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/engage/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Celebrate National Poetry Month with 50 Newly Available Audio Recordings<br /></strong></p>
<p>The Archive of Recorded Poetry and Literature at the Library of Congress dates back to 1943 and contains nearly two thousand recordings of poets and prose writers participating in literary events at the Library&rsquo;s Capitol Hill campus as well as sessions at the Library&rsquo;s Recording Laboratory. New recordings added for 2020 include a 1978 reunion reading featuring 13 of our Consultants in Poetry, and Gwendolyn Brooks reading poems (including the iconic &ldquo;We Real Cool&rdquo;) in the Jefferson Recording Laboratory in 1961.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/collections/archive-of-recorded-poetry-and-literature/about-this-collection/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Visit the archive site</a>.<br /><a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/catbird/2020/04/celebrate-national-poetry-month-with-50-newly-streaming-audio-recordings/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Discover more on this blog post</a>.</p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Try Activity Kits for the Whole Family<br /></strong></p>
<p>Encourage kids of all ages to use their creativity to complete activities inspired by the Library&rsquo;s collections. With simple items found around the house and items from our website, kids can Cook Up History, Make a Mini-Book, Color Our Collections, and so much more. Visit the Resources for Family Engagement page to download activity kits and get started today.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/families/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/families/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Join the Effort: By the People</strong></p>
<p>We are grateful to all those who transcribe and review pages on the Library's virtual volunteering project By the People launched in 2018. As of the Library&rsquo;s 220th birthday today, volunteers have transcribed over 125,000 pages from the papers of suffragists including Mary Church Terrell, Lucy Stone, and Susan B Anthony, civil rights activist Rosa Parks, poet Walt Whitman, President Abraham Lincoln, and many others. Once a whole item such as a journal or letter is complete, it is brought back to loc.gov where it radically improves search and discovery for patrons, and accessibility those who use screen readers.</p>
<p><a href="https://crowd.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://crowd.loc.gov/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Preservation Week<br /></strong></p>
<p>National Preservation Week is April 26 &ndash; May 2. Preservation of the world's largest collection is accomplished through a broad range of activities distributed across the Library. Learn more about these preservation activities and the work to keep the collections available for the next 220 years and beyond.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/preservation/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/preservation/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Coronavirus Updates from the Copyright Office<br /></strong></p>
<p>The Copyright Office has announced updated flexibility surrounding registration deposits and timing provisions for those affected by COVID-19 as outlined in the Coronavirus Aid, Relief, and Economic Security (CARES) Act. Visit the Copyright Office COVID-19 page for more info.</p>
<p align="left"><a href="https://www.copyright.gov/coronavirus/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.copyright.gov/coronavirus/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285068/gov-header_original.jpg" alt="Library of Congress" title="" width="600" height="190" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Support the Library</strong></p>
<p>We are more grateful than ever for all that you do to keep us strong. Whether you support the Library with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of our collective past, present, and future.</p>
<p>If you haven't yet had a chance to give and you're in a position to donate, please consider making a gift at<span style="color: #1f497d;"> </span><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/donate</a>/<span style="color: #1f497d;"></span>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Apr 2020 14:43:14 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>A Message from the Librarian of Congress</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">42326672</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=ealn</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285149/cdh2_original.jpg" alt="Carla D. Hayden, Librarian of Congress" title="" width="210" height="210" style="float: left;" />Friends,</p>
<p>I hope that you are taking care or yourselves and your families as we settle into a new normal amid the COVID-19 pandemic. During these challenging times, the Library of Congress buildings remain closed to the public with all public events currently canceled through May 11. However, while our physical doors may be closed, we are still here for you.</p>
<p>The Library&rsquo;s vast online resources offer unlimited opportunities to discover something new for families, educators, researchers and anyone curious enough to join us.</p>
<p>Our dedicated and talented Library staff remain hard at work, remotely expanding online collections, cataloging, registering Copyrights and advising Congress, while also developing new virtual events and offerings that offer <a href="https://www.loc.gov/engage/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">new ways to engage</a>. Below you will find just a few ways that you can continue to find excellent programs and content from the Library.</p>
<p>Thank you for your support of the Library of Congress, and we invite you to continue to (virtually) engage with us safely at home. Visit our web site for <a href="https://loc.gov/about/pandemic-information/for-public/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full, up-to-date information about our response to COVID-19</a>.</p>
<p>Sincerely,<br />Carla Hayden, Librarian of Congress</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285086/dav-jason_original.png" alt="Image of Dav Pilkey &amp; Jason Reynolds" title="" width="600" height="194" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Engage!</strong></p>
<p>Children&rsquo;s author and illustrator Dav Pilkey shares new activities and exciting videos every Friday. DETAILS: <a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-026/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-026/</a></p>
<p>Jason Reynolds, the National Ambassador for Young People&rsquo;s Literature, shares his passion for storytelling through a new monthly GRAB THE MIC newsletter and "Write. Right. Rite.," a twice-weekly "Grab the Mic" video series. DETAILS: <a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-028/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-028/</a></p>
<p>Poets Laureate Joy Harjo, Robert Pinsky, Natasha Trethewey and Juan Felipe Herrera talk to Ron Charles of The Washington Post about "The Poetry of Home" in a series for National Poetry Month. DETAILS: <a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-029/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/item/prn-20-029/</a></p>
<p>Find more ways to engage with authors you love and connect to the Library&rsquo;s resources from anywhere in the world on this new, frequently-updated page: <a href="https://loc.gov/engage/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://loc.gov/engage/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285153/screen-shot-2020-04-10-at-12-42-55-pm_original.png" alt="Rosa Parks" title="" width="210" height="210" style="float: left;" />Rosa Parks: In Her Own Words &ndash; Visit the Exhibition Online</strong></p>
<p>Visit fascinating exhibitions online including our current exhibition on Rosa Parks which showcases rarely seen materials that offer an intimate view of Rosa Parks and documents her life and activism&mdash;creating a rich opportunity for viewers to discover new dimensions to their understanding of this seminal figure.</p>
<p><a href="https://www.loc.gov/exhibitions/rosa-parks-in-her-own-words/about-this-exhibition/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://www.loc.gov/exhibitions/rosa-parks-in-her-own-words/about-this-exhibition/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>For Educators: Classroom Materials &amp; Online Office Hours</strong></p>
<p>The Library of Congress offers classroom materials and professional development to help teachers effectively use primary sources from the Library's vast digital collections in their teaching. <a href="https://loc.gov/teachers/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://loc.gov/teachers/</a></p>
<p>Join Library of Congress education specialists for 20-minute topical presentations followed by Q&amp;A every Tuesday and Thursday 2-3 p.m. ET. <a href="https://loc.gov/teachers/professionaldevelopment/office-hours/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://loc.gov/teachers/professionaldevelopment/office-hours/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285053/collect-head_original.png" alt="Image of Washington, D.C." title="" width="600" height="223" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Explore Digital Collections</strong></p>
<p>Dive into the Library&rsquo;s digital collections to explore just about any topic imaginable. Click through historical portraits and cityscape photographs, listen to sound recordings and oral histories, study American history and world cultures, discover local history and folklife traditions, explore maps, music, manuscripts and so much more. With digitized collections of more than 2.4 million items, it&rsquo;s all at your fingertips.</p>
<p><a href="https://loc.gov/collections/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://loc.gov/collections/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Coronavirus Resource Guide</strong></p>
<p><span style="color: #333333;">This is intended as a guide to laws, regulations and executive actions in the United States, at both the federal and the state level, and in various countries with respect to the new coronavirus and its spread. It also includes links to the Library's Congressional Research Service reports that provide information to Congress about the novel coronavirus. In addition, we provide links to relevant federal agency websites. </span></p>
<p><a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/law/2020/03/coronavirus-resource-guide/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://blogs.loc.gov/law/2020/03/coronavirus-resource-guide/</a></p>
<hr />
<p><strong>Ask a Librarian &ndash; We&rsquo;re Open for (Online) Business</strong></p>
<p>Most of the Library&rsquo;s reference librarians are now teleworking in response to the coronavirus pandemic.&nbsp;But our <a href="https://www.loc.gov/rr/askalib/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ask a Librarian service</a> remains open! Submit questions to receive research or reference help.</p>
<p>More: <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/loc/2020/03/ask-a-librarian-were-open-for-online-business/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">https://blogs.loc.gov/loc/2020/03/ask-a-librarian-were-open-for-online-business/</a>&shy;</p>
<hr />
<p><strong><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2020/04/3285068/gov-header_original.jpg" alt="Library of Congress" title="" width="600" height="190" /></strong></p>
<p><strong>Support the Library</strong></p>
<p>Thank you for being an important part of the Library of Congress family. During these difficult times, we are more grateful than ever for your support. Your generosity helps keep us strong and allows us to be ready when crises lift. Please stay safe. Visit <a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate/?loclr=ealn" target="_blank" rel="noopener">loc.gov/donate</a> and consider making a gift to ensure the Library&rsquo;s resources help everyone who needs them.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2019 11:00:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Thanks for Your Support!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">41049881</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974057/mrr-600x227_original.png" alt="Image of researcher in Main Reading Room" title="" width="600" height="227" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974058/ignite-600x_original.png" alt="IGNITE THE POWER OF IDEAS!" title="" width="600" height="85" /></span></p>
<p><strong><font size="5">Thank You!<br /></font></strong></p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">Thank you for all you do to support the nation&rsquo;s Library. With new books, films, and music arriving every day, the Library of Congress is your place to discover new ideas. Whether you support us with a gift or simply by spreading the word about what we do, you help us in our mission to connect millions of people around the world with the stories of the world&rsquo;s past, present, and future.</p>
<p style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;" align="left"><strong>Spread the word and encourage your friends and family to visit us online or in person and make a gift to the nation&rsquo;s library</strong><strong><span>&nbsp;</span>today!</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Dec 2019 09:15:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Make Your Gift Before We Close the Books on 2019!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">41049710</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/12/2992177/wow-700x350_original.png" alt="Excited people looking at collection materials" title="" width="600" height="300" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974058/ignite-600x_original.png" alt="IGNITE THE POWER OF IDEAS!" title="" width="600" height="85" /></span></p>
<p><strong><font size="5">Make Your Gift Before We Close the Books on 2019<br /></font></strong></p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">The Library of Congress is your place to discover new ideas. Visit our new exhibitions, join us for our events and educational programs and participate in our activities that connect you with millions of people around the world.</p>
<p style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;" align="left"><strong>Join the community of people that helps ignite the power of ideas and make your tax-deductible donation today!</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 09:00:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>TODAY: Ignite the Power of Ideas</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">40789914</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/12/2992177/wow-700x350_original.png" alt="Excited people looking at collection materials" title="" width="600" height="300" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974058/ignite-600x_original.png" alt="IGNITE THE POWER OF IDEAS!" title="" width="600" height="85" /></span></p>
<p><strong><font size="5">Make Your Gift to the Nation's Library</font></strong></p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">The day has arrived&mdash;<strong>#GivingTuesday</strong>&mdash;a day when your gift makes a difference and a statement.</p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">The Library of Congress depends on the support of people like you for its exhibitions, programs, events and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with its unique collections, experts and services.</p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;">The Library of Congress is your gateway to discovery. New books, films and music arrive every day. New research and new stories reveal themselves every day.<span>&nbsp;</span><span style="color: #333333; text-decoration: none;"><strong>Join us on this #GivingTuesday, December 3, to help bring new ideas and experiences to life!</strong></span></p>
<p class="gdp" style="margin: 10px 0px 0px; padding: 0px; color: #333333; font-family: Arial, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; font-style: normal; font-variant-ligatures: normal; font-variant-caps: normal; font-weight: 400; letter-spacing: normal; orphans: 2; text-align: left; text-indent: 0px; text-transform: none; white-space: normal; widows: 2; word-spacing: 0px; -webkit-text-stroke-width: 0px; background-color: #ffffff; text-decoration-style: initial; text-decoration-color: initial;"><strong>Spread the word<span>&nbsp;</span></strong>today and<strong><span>&nbsp;</span>encourage your friends and family<span>&nbsp;</span></strong>to make a gift to the nation&rsquo;s library, your gateway to understanding the world.</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Nov 2019 09:42:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  119 YEARS AGO: "The Gobble," San Francisco Call," Nov. 24, 1901</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">40792597</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-11-24/ed-1/seq-8/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Not enjoying the Thanksgiving spirit? Here's an unusual poem by Clarence V. Odell describing the turkey-eat-turkey dynamic of a 'gobble,' another name for a flock of the big birds (also known as a 'rafter').</p>
<p>"NINE greedy gobblers having a fete,<br />One ate his head off, then there were eight...."</p>
<p>Pity the turkeys... it rarely ends well for them!</p>
<p><a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn85066387/1901-11-24/ed-1/seq-8/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="Read more about it" rel="noopener">Read more about it</a> and follow us all the time on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:29:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Ignite the Power of Ideas</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">40752625</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974057/mrr-600x227_original.png" alt="Image of researcher in Main Reading Room" title="" width="600" height="227" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2019/11/2974058/ignite-600x_original.png" alt="IGNITE THE POWER OF IDEAS!" title="" width="600" height="85" /></span></p>
<p>On<strong> Tuesday, December 3</strong>, we ask you to make a gift to the Library of Congress in celebration of #GivingTuesday&mdash;a global giving movement.</p>
<p>Your gift supports exhibitions, events, programs and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with the unique collections, experts and services here at the nation&rsquo;s library.</p>
<p>The Library of Congress is your gateway to discovery. New books, films and music arrive every day. New research and new stories reveal themselves every day. <strong>Help bring new ideas and experiences to life with your gift this #GivingTuesday, December 3.</strong></p>
<p>Save the date to make your gift and <a href="https://www.loc.gov/?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">visit loc.gov</a> to see what&rsquo;s new!</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/donate?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2019 15:21:53 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Checking Out Baseballâ€™s World Series in Washington 1924, 1925 and 1933</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">40389924</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F1%2F1924&amp;date2=10%2F10%2F1933&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=&amp;proxtext=washington+world+series&amp;proxdistance=10&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><font face="calibri,arial,sans-serif" size="3">Game 3 of the 2019 World Series gets underway in Washington, DC, tonite and we're excited! Not since 1933 has Washington hosted the championship games of &ldquo;America&rsquo;s great pastime,&rdquo; baseball! <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&amp;dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F03%2F1924&amp;date2=10%2F11%2F1924&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=world+series&amp;proxtext=&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">In 1924</a>, Washington&rsquo;s then-home baseball team, the Washington Senators, won the series and earned bragging rights in 7 games against the New York Giants. Not quite so successful <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&amp;dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F06%2F1925&amp;date2=10%2F16%2F1925&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=world+series&amp;proxtext=&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="in 1925" rel="noopener">in 1925</a> and <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?state=&amp;dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F02%2F1933&amp;date2=10%2F08%2F1933&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=world+series&amp;proxtext=&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="1933" rel="noopener">1933</a> against the Pittsburgh Pirates and the Giants again, respectively, the nation&rsquo;s press still covered the sport in detail and with drama. Check out the newspaper coverage for each of these series or <a href="https://www.loc.gov/rr/news/topics/baseball.html?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="earlier World Series" rel="noopener">earlier World Series</a> and <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/search/pages/results/?dateFilterType=range&amp;date1=10%2F1%2F1924&amp;date2=10%2F10%2F1933&amp;language=&amp;ortext=&amp;andtext=&amp;phrasetext=&amp;proxtext=washington+world+series&amp;proxdistance=10&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="read more about it" rel="noopener">read more about it</a>! And be sure to follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm for more fun snippets of old news!</font></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2019 17:46:48 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: "FIRE! Destruction of Chicago!" Chicago Tribune, Oct. 11, 1871</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">40166993</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014064/1871-10-11/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Almost 150 years ago on October 8, 1871, the Great Fire of Chicago began in a small dwelling on "the west side"&nbsp; of the city. Two days later, as the conflagration finally died down, the Chicago Tribune printed a brief two-page issue, its first since the disaster began. Its own home offices devastated by the fire, after detailed descriptions of the destruction, the paper declared "CHICAGO SHALL RISE AGAIN." Discover more about how the nation responded to the news through <a href="https://guides.loc.gov/chronicling-america-great-chicago-fire/introduction?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="our Research Guide" rel="noopener">our Research Guide</a> and <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn82014064/1871-10-11/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="read more about it in the Chicago Tribune" rel="noopener">read more about it in the Chicago Tribune</a>!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 11:53:46 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers: CORRECTION - NEH Announces 2019 Awards for the National Digital Newspaper Program, Adding Partners in Rhode Island, Virgin Islands and Wyoming!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">39388374</guid>
      <link>https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>An error was made in a previous message regarding the number of partners to date in the National Digital Newspaper Program. Corrected message below:</p>
<p>The National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) <a href="https://links.govdelivery.com/track?type=click&amp;enid=ZWFzPTEmbXNpZD0mYXVpZD0mbWFpbGluZ2lkPTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmbWVzc2FnZWlkPU1EQi1QUkQtQlVMLTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmZGF0YWJhc2VpZD0xMDAxJnNlcmlhbD0xNjgwMjM1NiZlbWFpbGlkPWRldGhAbG9jLmdvdiZ1c2VyaWQ9ZGV0aEBsb2MuZ292JnRhcmdldGlkPSZmbD0mbXZpZD0mZXh0cmE9JiYm&amp;&amp;&amp;101&amp;&amp;&amp;https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide" target="_blank" rel="noopener">has announced 2019 National Digital Newspaper Program (NDNP) funding</a> for institutions representing 11 states to expand their selection and digitization of U.S. historic newspapers for contribution to the&nbsp;freely available <a href="https://links.govdelivery.com/track?type=click&amp;enid=ZWFzPTEmbXNpZD0mYXVpZD0mbWFpbGluZ2lkPTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmbWVzc2FnZWlkPU1EQi1QUkQtQlVMLTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmZGF0YWJhc2VpZD0xMDAxJnNlcmlhbD0xNjgwMjM1NiZlbWFpbGlkPWRldGhAbG9jLmdvdiZ1c2VyaWQ9ZGV0aEBsb2MuZ292JnRhcmdldGlkPSZmbD0mbXZpZD0mZXh0cmE9JiYm&amp;&amp;&amp;102&amp;&amp;&amp;https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Chronicling America online collection</a>, hosted by the <a href="https://www.loc.gov/" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">Library of Congress</a>. New partners in the program include the Providence Public Library (Rhode Island); the U.S. Virgin Islands (in partnership with the Universities of Florida and Puerto Rico); and the University of Wyoming (Laramie).&nbsp; Eight other participating institutions &ndash; Arkansas State Archives, Connecticut State Library, University of Delaware, University of Georgia, Minnesota Historical Society, Library of Virginia, West Virginia University and Wisconsin Historical Society - also received awards to expand their ongoing selection and digitization of newspapers from their state. Check out the <a href="https://links.govdelivery.com/track?type=click&amp;enid=ZWFzPTEmbXNpZD0mYXVpZD0mbWFpbGluZ2lkPTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmbWVzc2FnZWlkPU1EQi1QUkQtQlVMLTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmZGF0YWJhc2VpZD0xMDAxJnNlcmlhbD0xNjgwMjM1NiZlbWFpbGlkPWRldGhAbG9jLmdvdiZ1c2VyaWQ9ZGV0aEBsb2MuZ292JnRhcmdldGlkPSZmbD0mbXZpZD0mZXh0cmE9JiYm&amp;&amp;&amp;103&amp;&amp;&amp;https://www.neh.gov/sites/default/files/inline-files/NEH-Grant-Awards-August-2019-PDF.pdf" target="_blank" rel="noopener">full list of grants</a> for details. Since 2005, cultural institutions in 50 states and territories have joined the program, jointly sponsored by the NEH and LOC, and contributed more than 15 million digitized historical American newspaper pages, published between 1789 and 1963 in 19 different languages, to the collection.</p>
<p>Learn more about the <a href="https://links.govdelivery.com/track?type=click&amp;enid=ZWFzPTEmbXNpZD0mYXVpZD0mbWFpbGluZ2lkPTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmbWVzc2FnZWlkPU1EQi1QUkQtQlVMLTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmZGF0YWJhc2VpZD0xMDAxJnNlcmlhbD0xNjgwMjM1NiZlbWFpbGlkPWRldGhAbG9jLmdvdiZ1c2VyaWQ9ZGV0aEBsb2MuZ292JnRhcmdldGlkPSZmbD0mbXZpZD0mZXh0cmE9JiYm&amp;&amp;&amp;104&amp;&amp;&amp;https://www.loc.gov/ndnp/">National Digital Newspaper Program (NDNP)</a> or <a href="https://links.govdelivery.com/track?type=click&amp;enid=ZWFzPTEmbXNpZD0mYXVpZD0mbWFpbGluZ2lkPTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmbWVzc2FnZWlkPU1EQi1QUkQtQlVMLTIwMTkwODE2LjkxNzgwOTEmZGF0YWJhc2VpZD0xMDAxJnNlcmlhbD0xNjgwMjM1NiZlbWFpbGlkPWRldGhAbG9jLmdvdiZ1c2VyaWQ9ZGV0aEBsb2MuZ292JnRhcmdldGlkPSZmbD0mbXZpZD0mZXh0cmE9JiYm&amp;&amp;&amp;105&amp;&amp;&amp;https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/">explore American history through Chronicling America</a> and read more about it! Follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Aug 2019 10:00:01 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  NEH Announces 2019 Awards for the National Digital Newspaper Program, adding partners in Rhode Island, Virgin Islands and Wyoming!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">39387099</guid>
      <link>https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>The National Endowment for the Humanities (NEH) <a href="https://www.neh.gov/news/neh-announces-29-million-215-humanities-projects-nationwide" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">has announced 2019 National Digital Newspaper Program (NDNP) funding</a> for institutions representing 11 states to expand their selection and digitization of U.S. historic newspapers for contribution to the&nbsp;freely available <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">Chronicling America online collection</a>, hosted by the Library of Congress. New partners in the program include the Providence Public Library (Rhode Island); the US Virgin Islands (in partnership with the Universities of Florida and Puerto Rico); and the University of Wyoming (Laramie).&nbsp; Eight other participating institutions &ndash; Arkansas State Archives, Connecticut State Library, University of Delaware, University of Georgia, Minnesota Historical Society, Library of Virginia, West Virginia University and Wisconsin Historical Society - also received awards to expand their ongoing selection and digitization of newspapers from their state. Check out the <a href="https://www.neh.gov/sites/default/files/inline-files/NEH-Grant-Awards-August-2019-PDF.pdf" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">full list of grants</a> for details. Since 2005, cultural institutions in 49 states and territories have joined the program, jointly sponsored by the NEH and LC, and contributed more than 15 million digitized historical American newspaper pages, published between 1789 and 1963 in 19 different languages, to the collection.</p>
<p>Learn more about the <a href="https://www.loc.gov/ndnp/">National Digital Newspaper Program (NDNP)</a> or <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/">explore American history through Chronicling America</a> and read more about it! Follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jul 2019 16:25:56 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  100 YEARS AGO: "Wilson Blocks Daylight Saving Appeal," The Evening World, July 12, 1919</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">38871710</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1919-07-12/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Daylight saving time went into effect in the United States on March 31, 1918 during World War I as part of the war effort and many thought it would end when the war ended. Farmers across the country petitioned to end national daylight saving time in 1919 but President Wilson vetoed the repeal stating it &ldquo;would be of very grave inconvenience to the country.&rdquo; He would go on to reject the bill a second time on August 15, 1919. <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1919-07-12/ed-1/seq-1/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="Read more about it" rel="noopener">Read more about it</a> and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2019 15:04:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  75 Years Ago: â€œALLIES SMASHING INLAND,â€ The Wilmington Morning Star, June 07, 1944</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">38383009</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78002169/1944-06-07/ed-1/seq-1/?eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Across the world on June 7, 1944, newspapers rushed to press with the first word on the Western Allied invasion of the beaches of Normandy in France. For days before, front pages in the homefront news were filled with word of Allied battles on all fronts with hints of an imminent invasion of the French coast. Finally on June 7, news arrived&hellip; &ldquo;ALLIES SMASHING INLAND&rdquo; declared the Wilmington Morning Star (Wilmington, DE). Follow the headlines from issue to issue and <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn78002169/1944-06-07/ed-1/seq-1/?eacam" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">read more about it</a>! (And then follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!)</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 May 2019 10:57:51 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Celebrate 15 Million Pages with Us! Find Out More and Join our Twitter #ChronAmParty Today (May 21)!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">38155249</guid>
      <link>http://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/05/chronicling-america-15-million-and-counting/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Join us in celebrating a new milestone in Chronicling America &ndash; 15 million pages freely available to all! You can find out more on <em>LC's </em><a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/05/chronicling-america-15-million-and-counting/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener"><em>Headlines and Heroes</em></a> blog and join the <a href="https://twitter.com/hashtag/chronamparty?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="Twitter" rel="noopener">#ChronAmParty on Twitter</a> all day Tuesday, May 21 (today!). Follow the threads and find out about all the fun kinds of &ldquo;15 Million&rdquo; things we&rsquo;ve discovered in Chronicling America &ndash; feel free to celebrate with us and tweet your own discoveries! Just add #ChronAmParty and #15MillionPages to your tweet to join the party!</p>
<p>We&rsquo;ve also been working on new ways to <a href="http://www.loc.gov/ndnp/data-visualizations/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">explore and visualize</a> what&rsquo;s available in Chronicling America and have included a sneak peek in <em>Headlines and Heroes </em>and a more in-depth explanation of these tools in the Library&rsquo;s <em><a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/thesignal/2019/05/visualizing-chronicling-america-data-15-million-pages-of-digitized-historical-newspapers/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" rel="noopener">The Signal</a></em> digital libraries blog. Understand and interact with our newspapers in a different way using maps, time-based views, charts of language and ethnic press in American newspapers and more!</p>
<p><a href="http://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/05/chronicling-america-15-million-and-counting/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">Read more about it</a> and follow us all the time on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 May 2019 14:57:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Happy National Chocolate Chip Cookie Day! (May 15)</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">38085692</guid>
      <link>https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2017236974/1940-10-10/ed-1/seq-19/#date1=1789&amp;index=19&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced&amp;language=&amp;sequence=0&amp;words=Chip+Chocolate+Cookies&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;date2=1963&amp;ortext=&amp;proxtext=chocolate+chip+cookie&amp;phrasetext=&amp;andtext=&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><font face="times new roman,times" size="3">Happy National Chocolate Chip Cookie Day! Have you made America&rsquo;s favorite cookie recently? How about trying out <a href="https://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/2017236974/1940-10-10/ed-1/seq-19/#date1=1789&amp;index=19&amp;rows=20&amp;searchType=advanced&amp;language=&amp;sequence=0&amp;words=Chip+Chocolate+Cookies&amp;proxdistance=5&amp;date2=1963&amp;ortext=&amp;proxtext=chocolate+chip+cookie&amp;phrasetext=&amp;andtext=&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="link" rel="noopener">this 1940 recipe</a> from the Roanoke Rapids Herald (Roanoke Rapids, NC)? Chop your own chocolate and read more about it! Follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm! </font><span style="font-size: 11.0pt; font-family: 'Calibri',sans-serif; color: #1f497d;"><br /></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 15:50:12 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Celebrate International Women's Day With Us!</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">37043146</guid>
      <link>https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/03/international-womens-day/?loclr=eacam</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>Celebrate International Women's Day today with us and explore how change-making women in American history appeared in the contemporary news using the Chronicling America historic newspaper collection. Our most recent post in <em>Headlines and Heroes</em> highlights fifteen amazing American women, including Clara Barton, Ida B. Wells, Marie Curie, Elizabeth Cady Stanton and, of course, investigative journalist Nellie Bly. Use the linked Recommended Topic guides to learn more about them and make your own discoveries. <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2019/03/international-womens-day/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="Read more about" rel="noopener">Read more about them</a> and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Jan 2019 16:37:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  86 YEARS AGO: â€œPopular Popcorn,â€ The Midland Journal, February 17, 1933</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">36256316</guid>
      <link>http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060136/1933-02-17/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1789&amp;index=16&amp;rows=20&amp;words=POPCORN+popcorn+Popcorn&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=popcorn&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p>In honor of National Popcorn Day on Jan. 19, here&rsquo;s a quick rundown from 1933 of some fun ways to incorporate more grains into your diet! There&rsquo;s of course the traditional style of popcorn for snacking, &ldquo;popped while you wait, with a generous pour of melted butter and a big shake of salt&rdquo; according to the Midland Journal (Rising Sun, MD). But why not enjoy some popcorn &ldquo;merrily floating on the surface of creamy soups,&rdquo; or combine popcorn, cheese, and mayonnaise for cheeseballs in a fruit salad! <a href="http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn89060136/1933-02-17/ed-1/seq-7/#date1=1789&amp;index=16&amp;rows=20&amp;words=POPCORN+popcorn+Popcorn&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1963&amp;proxtext=popcorn&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1" target="_blank" title="" rel="noopener">Read more about it</a>, check out some recipes and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!<span style="color: #1f497d;"></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Mon, 31 Dec 2018 07:15:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Still Time for Last-Minute Giving</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35915321</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263008/spark-topper_original.png" alt="Help Spark a Lifelong Adventure of Learning" width="700" height="314" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px;">The Library&rsquo;s resolution for 2019 is to offer more opportunities to engage lifelong learners like you with our unique treasures and programs. <strong>Make your gift before we close the books on 2018!</strong></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">Your gift supports FREE exhibitions, events, programs, and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with our unique collections, experts, and services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><strong>The Library of Congress is your library</strong>, your gateway to understanding the world. There is so much to discover, not only the nation&rsquo;s memory, but the world&rsquo;s&mdash;information from all corners of the earth, in more than 470 languages. With millions of items available online, you can access the Library&rsquo;s treasures from anywhere and connect with us in ways that are personally relevant and valuable.</span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Dec 2018 08:00:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Make a Year-End Gift to the Nation's Library</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35915275</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263274/make-topper_original.png" alt="Make Your Gift to the Nation's Library" title="Giving 2" width="700" height="257" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></span></p>
<p style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px;">The Library&rsquo;s resolution for 2019 is to offer more opportunities to engage lifelong learners like you with our unique treasures and programs. <strong>Make your gift before we close the books on 2018!</strong></p>
<p style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px;">Your gift can:</p>
<ul style="text-align: start;">
<li style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; margin: 0 0 7px;">Inspire curiosity in children to read more books and reflect on the&nbsp;power of books to change their lives</li>
<li style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; margin: 0 0 7px;">Ignite thoughtful conversation among current and future generations of students and scholars</li>
<li style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px; margin: 0 0 7px;">Illuminate the minds of people like you who use the resources of the nation's Library here in Washington or via the Internet in their own homes and communities</li>
</ul>
<p style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px;">With the help of supporters like you, we can spark the imagination of people of all ages with programs that open the Library&rsquo;s doors wide to all.</p>
<p style="text-align: left; color: #333333; font-family: arial, helvetica, sans-serif; font-size: 14px;"><strong>Join us TODAY by making your 2018 tax-deductible donation, and together we&rsquo;ll spark a lifelong adventure of learning.</strong></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev" target="_blank" title="DONATE NOW" rel="noopener"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Dec 2018 09:16:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  Join the National Digital Newspaper Program in 2019! Applications due Jan. 15, 2019</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35782124</guid>
      <link>http://1.usa.gov/1ye8EKz</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; font-size: 8.5pt;">from <a href="https://twitter.com/NEHgov" class="account-group js-account-group js-action-profile js-user-profile-link js-nav" data-user-id="155987003"><span class="username u-dir u-textTruncate" data-aria-label-part="">@<strong>NEHgov</strong></span></a> on Twitter: </span><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; font-size: 8.5pt;">Be part of the National Digital Newspaper Program (NDNP), a partnership between National Endowment for the Humanities and the Library of Congress to create a digital resource of newspapers published between 1690 and 1963, from all the states and U.S. territories. Applications due Jan 15: <a href="https://t.co/ST3DfBUkcR" target="_blank" title="http://1.usa.gov/1ye8EKz" class="twitter-timeline-link" data-expanded-url="http://1.usa.gov/1ye8EKz" rel="noopener"><span class="tco-ellipsis"></span><span class="invisible">http://</span><span class="js-display-url">1.usa.gov/1ye8EKz</span><span class="invisible"></span><span class="tco-ellipsis"><span class="invisible">&nbsp;</span></span></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Nov 2018 07:00:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Make Your Gift to the Nation's Library</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35429411</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263274/make-topper_original.png" alt="Make Your Gift to the Nation's Library" title="Giving 2" width="700" height="257" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">The day has arrived&mdash;<strong>#GivingTuesday</strong>&mdash;a day when your gift makes a difference and a statement. </span></p>
<p class="gdp" style="line-height: 140%;"><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">The Library of Congress depends on donations from people like you to produce exhibitions, events, programs, and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with our unique collections, experts, and services.</span></p>
<p class="gdp" style="line-height: 140%;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">Gifts bring the Library to life </span></strong><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">with music, dance, film, sound, culture, scholarship, research, discussions and ideas. Your gift, no matter the size, will support diverse programs that are entirely <strong>FREE</strong> for everyone to enjoy, and will make the Library&rsquo;s treasures and services more accessible. </span></p>
<p class="gdp" style="line-height: 140%;"><strong><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">Help spread the word today and encourage your friends and family to make a gift to the nation&rsquo;s library</span></strong><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">, your gateway to understanding the world!</span></p>
<p class="gdp" style="line-height: 140%;"><em><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">#GivingTuesday is a global day of giving fueled by the power of social media and collaboration.</span></em><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; line-height: 140%; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Nov 2018 15:37:06 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Chronicling America:  Historic American Newspapers:  100 YEARS AGO: "Menu and Recipes for Your 'Victory' Thanksgiving Dinner," The Evening World, Nov. 26, 1918</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35463812</guid>
      <link>http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-11-26/ed-1/seq-14/#date1=1918&amp;index=1&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Recipes+Thanksgiving&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1918&amp;proxtext=thanksgiving+recipe&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><font face="times new roman,times" size="3"><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; font-size: 8.5pt;">Just a few weeks after the the signing of the armistice with Germany on November 11, 1918, ending military action in World War One, Americans prepared to celebrate their traditional Thanksgiving with new appreciation for a "day of thankful prayer... and joyous feasting." Although still restricted by wartime rationing, the Evening World (New York, NY) asked chefs of major New York City hotels to contribute their best recipes to honor the Allied leaders responsible for victory and the war's end....<a href="http://chroniclingamerica.loc.gov/lccn/sn83030193/1918-11-26/ed-1/seq-14/#date1=1918&amp;index=1&amp;rows=20&amp;words=Recipes+Thanksgiving&amp;searchType=basic&amp;sequence=0&amp;state=&amp;date2=1918&amp;proxtext=thanksgiving+recipe&amp;y=0&amp;x=0&amp;dateFilterType=yearRange&amp;page=1" target="_blank" title="Read more about it " rel="noopener">Read more about it</a> and try some Roast Turkey a la Pershing! For more Thanksgiving recipes see our recent Headlines and Heroes blog for <a href="https://blogs.loc.gov/headlinesandheroes/2018/11/10-thanksgiving-recipes-you-may-not-have-tried/?loclr=eacam" target="_blank" title="&quot;10 Thanksgiving Recipes You May Not Have Tried&quot;" rel="noopener">"10 Thanksgiving Recipes You May Not Have Tried"</a> and follow us on Twitter @librarycongress #ChronAm!</span></font><span><span style="color: black; font-family: 'Verdana','sans-serif'; font-size: 8.5pt;"></span></span></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 12:52:36 -0600</pubDate>
      <title>Spark a Lifelong Adventure of Learning</title>
      <guid isPermaLink="false">35429359</guid>
      <link>https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev</link>
      <description>
        <![CDATA[<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263008/spark-topper_original.png" alt="Help Spark a Lifelong Adventure of Learning" width="700" height="314" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">This year is the second year the Library of Congress is participating in <strong>#GivingTuesday</strong>&mdash;a global giving movement. On <strong>Tuesday, November 27</strong>, we are asking you to make a gift to spark a lifelong adventure of learning. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">Your gift supports FREE exhibitions, events, programs, and activities that connect millions of people across the nation and around the world with our unique collections, experts, and services. </span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><strong>The Library of Congress is your library</strong>, your gateway to understanding the world. There is so much to discover, not only the nation&rsquo;s memory, but the world&rsquo;s&mdash;information from all corners of the earth, in more than 470 languages. With millions of items available online, you can access the Library&rsquo;s treasures from anywhere and connect with us in ways that are personally relevant and valuable.</span></p>
<h2 style="text-align: center; margin: 0in 0in 7.5pt 0in;"><span style="font-size: 16.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: black;">Save the Date to Make Your Gift!</span></h2>
<p><em><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;">Celebrated on the Tuesday following Thanksgiving (in the U.S.) and the widely recognized shopping events Black Friday and Cyber Monday, #GivingTuesday kicks off the charitable season, when many focus on their holiday and end-of-year giving.</span></em><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"></span></p>
<p><span style="font-size: 10.5pt; font-family: 'Arial',sans-serif; color: #333333;"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/philanthropy/online-donation/year-end?loclr=eadev"><img src="https://content.govdelivery.com/attachments/fancy_images/USLOC/2018/11/2263104/donate-now_original.png" alt="Donate Now" title="" width="164" height="49" style="display: block; margin-left: auto; margin-right: auto;" /></a></span></p>]]>
      </description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
